Can you guys here you're right?
So, just make sure we are all.
In the right place.
...is what
...should know about troubleshooting identity scenarios for?
...active directory so when you have
problems with authentication authorization you don't know what to do you in the right place
this is where we're going to discuss body and the.
Rationale for this presentation is that.
Whenever developers are.
Building applications for the clouding they have some identity's and...
eventually you're going to hit the problem...going to have some is configuration somewhere some problem
your called something's not working and very often way more often
then we would hope people see that error message
in they don't know-how to go from there to understanding what's broken
diagnose...fixing it.
And, that's a terrible experience right because the worst thing for
developers this philly helpful is like I can't.
I can solve these myself and what's even more interesting is when we
seek with those guys and walk with them through
how we trouble shoot this and how we find problem the reaction is always,
always something like well I had no idea was that super-high could
...see that so obviously this is not rocket science
it's something that everybody can do but something there's not working
when this throughout this problems happen and I think there are two ways we to parts of
the solution to this bad experience one part is there are lots of improvements
...happening right now as we speak in the product the product teams are doinga
bunch of improvements in the user experience
...the way you register and app the error messages documentation tooling all of these
is happening right now in will get better but no matter how bad better that gets we
believe I believe there are certain foundational knowledge?
Areas that every developer who is working on cloud applications
should have because that we our people to just they face a problem like this
...made them feel completely lost they know-how to navigate that problem in this is not
just microsoft in those protocols are everywhere so a lot of what we're going to talk
about here applies to pretty much whatever you role in
the with cloud identity protocols in general.
So, the way we organized is a presentation
...ensure the remember to singer evaluation later.
We collected for the past year.
We collected the most common questions developers bring to us like I
...how to do this item nowhere to go to do this right.
And, we broke it down to...so I will start with some basic concepts this is not a
tutorial presentation not going to...how to build an application four-zero
...wire up with a esri the vertebra...is doing
to presentations there's one after lunch where he's going to do that is going to while can be
viewed applications...show how-to-do-it I'm not going there but I just want-to make sure
...all at the same
pages some basic things before I start talking about questions and answers and troubleshooting then we
...if you're a frequent...with questions about very basic stuff like,
for example, I don't even know where to grow to find
called samples right let's talk about in the brief.
...each the level to questions which is a little bit of
how qi selected a couple of questions there very common questions that developers usually go
the wrong-way instead of going the right way so I want to show what's the wrong-way what's the right way
in y then the fun starts where I have a
...plus broken epsy right now here that are
...fix one by one with you guys that's the
...the through the real troubleshooting part of it they level for is
...the troubleshooting...the more.
Advance...where people really few...they don't know what to do and I want to
show those things are not
ss hard is the initially look so it's a very
...presentation I think I have about sixty or some heights here so
...will be interesting and, I price will be a lot of useful info that you guys can take away
from there so let's start with a very brief.
He story of authentication
for many years the way applications solved
the authentication problem was just putting username or password
...a form right you type your credentials and some custom
...happens behind-the-scenes...those
user mimic passwords and do something to validate that but the problem is what happens
behind-the-scenes because the way this applications work requires the
...to have access to your user name and password?
At that point there is no control
over what happens worker credentials anymore but we cannot make any
guarantees because who knows what...code is the signing to do here
right anything could happen for example, a developer
might think that ...might be a good idea to go and cash your credentials
...custom database write...
Unprotected and we all know what happens after that we have
stories and stories about companies that really have the entire ip the
entire business jeopardize because there was a least of username passwords
encrypted somewhere so we can't control that we have these
username password boxes that we need to get rid of them and...the common
...most cloud providers that we remove those things we put a
browser.
And, the browser ...web applications even...the browser goes to measure ed
and says I want to authenticate this user write a center hr hb
...and say I want to log on...run the application block and the response say
okay here's the logging form for that user write.
The user types things and password and this is protected from the application
code there's no way the application code can actually go in and redesigning password so these
are far more secure thing we're.
We're outsourcing
the ltd creation job to somewhere we trust and removing that problem from the
applications self right we submit that username and password back
...their beer bunch of steps their validating consenting and
then eventually all gary ultra is a shun code back...this part of http three
...a re-direct right and saying okay here's your authorization code
...I'm telling you I'm happy with whoever these user is
you can close...looking form...let's move on and then with this authorization
called the application can goal and request access tokens
for specific resources give me an access tokens for sharepoint align
give-me an excess token for exchange align for your secure web service so one right that's
...we do about
a delta realization part of it and this is the basics of
...basically that's what...right it's not very different...name
your platform...a single protocol and the reason why I'm showing this little
...of request...is that most of what are we talking about movie
forward in terms of problems and solutions has to do with something around one
of these steps...of the steps is not...issued so having this picturing
...mind is eighty percent of the job in terms of troubleshooting it
right so, some.
Some important take awaits
our for the same reason you don't see the...with your user name
and password because you can't control what's going to happen there you shouldn't put here is
...posturing some custom...some custom epidural even though you don't even know who
built it right because there's no way you come to you can control what happens there.
Knowing this sequence of http
requests eds most of...you need to figure out what's
broken help fix it...interesting thing is fiddler
...your best frame there and when it comes to troubleshooting
...hitler's great or...twelve your browser network
great ways of detecting what's broken but be careful you're going to
ask for help in a public forum and you base your filler logs
there remember that was captured...your logan proxies your user name
and password are there right so...
Think about...we choose running parser using how many people will be reading that
thing but you mold them, you know, what they can do with it so remember that's a lot of
since the information that you are capturing that...feeder log right?
So, let's start with the lever one questions.
So, lever one questions.
...room questions where do I find good called samples for
So, we embrace get hub did help is becoming the place where
microsoft really publishes all source...we can get just make
sayings forget great feedback from developers we interact with them we receive contributions
...and measuring the has a proper
area for samples and it's just great like, for example,
instead of going...speedup multiplication from zero adding the right get packages adding
the right configuration and then coding my application I just
go-there search for a speedup met by ppi open id connect there's already an application
with rewrite the get back...are just download that make my configurations and I'm done so
...faster than create and application from zero and one of the cool things if you in
both of those samples when you scroll down to the read me...gate hub
they tell you how they got to that point like this these are the steps we wintel
visual studio from zero to get to the sample...have here so it can follow the same steps
into that in...so...it's great-great way of learning how things get
them super common question how do I leak my office rather sixty-five directory
with my measure ad directory whenever you have an officer
...sixty-five subscription your users are already
saved in measuring the...a measure...there we just don't make it so obvious but
...there so assume your company already has office
...five and now you go and sign up for ager
in those are different things they don't see each other they don't know each other how can you tell as
your you already have these directory...to use in seed over a
measure what you need first is a microsoft account you need
and outlook dot com windows live an account that you set as a man
an administrator for your...your subscription you have to...with that account cannot
...ad account otherwise this feature won't show up by...with
...microsoft account you go to measure ed and say I
want to create a new directory and then you have
an option which is use existing directory
write use existing directory when you choose that option what as you do is it
...logical off from the portal and then rescue to
...with whatever eases the manager...from that
director...trying to add where you have to prove you own that thing it's yours so
you log offer the logo with the admin from that directory then.
...link is done then you can go back treasury
...treasure portal and you see our new directory created
...diseases...least directories these
are new directory and you can see you are office applications here just like you can
custom applications the office applications are there too so now you can do cool things like,
for example,
an application that can authenticate your user and then go talk to one
...for business on behalf of the user go talk to exchange
...of health of the user to your custom web...eb ad becomes that
...that connects all...building blocks together it's a fundamental part
of these ecosystem and that's how you bind both into a single
...can do that in multiple subscriptions at microsoft we have thousands of
a asia subscriptions they all can look at our microsoft-dot-com directory
we can all go...see the applications there so level
to questions how do I do stuff let's see so.
I need to create a background task.
That we access scanning...exchange align so background tasks.
It means there's no you why there's no ui hi my going-to
...if I don't have the web browser with the
...passwords so we can do that
everything show before well the answer is we are not logging a user
...application so the application itself
...authenticate itself right with the advocate recall ep aidid application
identity any this application have special privileges that are different
...a user privilege so, for example, user can us authorizing application to
work on behalf of that user which is what we call delegated permissions when you look at
...see...delegate
...permissions here so those are repair missions...user allow these
...to go to my in-box and exchange align
on might be health that's the right but we have the application-level permissions
where we say well these application who have permissions to read all the
...in my organization are very special
...application so the application has to prove itself I
m really this application that supposed to have this permissions this is done via a certificate
...applications configure with the certificate...ghostly.
Improves itself as an application any...like excess tokens
...for users and you can go talk to the same services the same things
we would talk normally as...user base application and that's how you make it work
and can even work across directories...have multiple and...that's?
Why I'm talking about it's because very often
delay developers try to solve this problem is putting username
...interface authenticate the user grabbed access token saving some data
...and try to keep refreshing background don't ever do that that's going to break
that's insecure that's just don't do that right there proper ways of doing this
without capturing custom access tokens and
doing some face ecosystem thing to try to keep them alive that doesn't work right?
Which library should be used authenticate star?
With leisurely here's a simple rule.
If you have a native...a client application of any kind...to show that...
a ui usually the right way of doing is using adjective director of
education library right we have it for ios android windows javascript
...we have it for a bunch of platforms super
easy it does a whole lot of stuff for you that you don't have to worry body refreshing tokens
...caching talking...don't have to goal every single time treasury...to get
...token a super easy-to-use three lines of...in your
don up so that's the that's the library usually us
...for the you why base loading for the user to authenticate if
...on the server-side if you're in your web api and you need to validate and
excess token so the...you is given access...make sure does access stockings body there are many different ways
you can do this esp dot net my favorite ways using owing...killeen and
my favorite protocol would be open id connect because it's just so much easier it's like a whilst with
a bunch of standards on top of it so it makes it so much easier to set it up so that
would take care of validating tokens make sure there are kl letting them go on each from you
are web service now you need to...talk...one
dry for business now you need...excess token four-wheel-drive for business then
...going to use a though...going to say well I just got this call from the client I have these
excess token I need to exchange that for a mater excess token lets me talk to
one dry for business sorry...do that requests tokens for you if you are
...on any platform that we for some reason don't have a library for you
go to these url look at the protocols we support right open id
...fair that setter and find a library that does that and a
you eventually you find a library...we support one of these protocols and you'll be fine right that's the rule
we...personally follow to figure out which
...what I should use for eachlibrary.
And, again, look, at the code samples...help.
What if I have a...again I don't have a you why I have id to write
and automated best I need to automate the test of my website I need to
simulate the user but there's no you why I'm not going to launch?
A browser...
With the you for the user to type the credentials and then move on how can
they simulate that how can I authenticate user...without
a ui turns out a delve that single averages some ancient he has this option...
headlines off where I have a user...object where I can really put a username
or password...authenticate and get
...toolkits keep in mind this is for automated pests consul
...our show this is not for you to go and figure out accustom
...why put some custom...but that's exactly the thing I just told you to
...you don't use it to do that because first of all is not
going to work are you run into problems and second it brings back
a whole series of problems I just discussed right we don't want
...called having access to use...passwords.
Let's go play with...then so, how much time?
Great...runtime.
So, let's look at the first scenario let-me jurists more
...here switched online books.
Ok.
So, I have one application here it's basically
...dot net.
And, actually we're going to do is launch.
Of private session because I want to clear all the
cookies.
And, I'll try to local.
...pipe microbe...if I remember.
I think that's it.
Q...career okay.
What is this?
So, it's saying the reply address.
Which is the address of my site does not match any reply addresses
...application?
What does it mean let's see?
When my application...the browser treasury the to
...measuring the hey when you finish your plumbing there...authenticate
the user send the browser here in this case?
My website where the user walls before right that's the reply address and this is
st treasury...so if I look at the that
...go back here if I look at the url.
And,...the redirect...that's it right
that's our client application telling measuring the when you finish logging
...the user...the user there that's fine that's
...the that's the right url that's where my applications running but actually these look at it
...say nobody told me...will be url for dessert so I would assume
...someone trying to finish this trying to steal pretend to be or ep and
...the user and I'll just
blockage right how do we fix that so what
...do is let me close this.
I will take this url.
That we...here.
I will go
to my application configurations which in this case is this one.
And, they can tell this is the right...because
...but because the client id matches
...my collide id so that's how I can be surethis is the right one.
Right.
And, what...do is say well let's see the reply
...can see indeed that urls not here?
Right.
So, what we do is saying actually this is okay you
can reply and you can have multiple that's okay right that's not a problem we'll save
Will run this again?
And, let me create a new...private session.
Just to see if that works.
Thanks all user.
Any works so we fix that right reply
...that's what that's what it means when you see...error it's a good heats that,
you know, what's broken there let's move on to the next problem.
For after
...that's similar to what I just did before so let me
open my order simple here simple number two.
Very common problem right launch my up.
Signing...name password.
And, boom for what happened here well if you look at
fiddler you see that...all everything went fine.
And, then you're trying to open these address.
Right.
Where is this coming from reply url
so what's happened is that my second application here
what's configured with a?
Redirect url that doesn't exist right I'm
...the browser to a page that?
Is nowhere so what I do here is fixing that I
can say well instead of going into this I can go to this
right because I know that page exists that url exist and that's how I fix
it right so below goal worked I can see the access
token being return I can see all the plumbing happening but then the browsers just
being told to go somewhere that that's doesn't exist that's how you fix that right?
Let's look at the third problem.
So, native apps let's talk about windows
a native epson and by the way the same problems happen with
ios android same thing same logic what I'm going to talk about here?
So, this is a windows.
Eight.
Application.
That does the same write it will do exactly like showing the leader animation I have a little
browser using a...puts a browser...in your.
Insider application and I will go and try to...here.
And, what and gary here is saying reply address...blah?
Is not a valid url?
Well, okay, and, if I look at this it really doesn't look like a
value euro for windows eight that's perfectly fine that's what windows
ad does he has this internal url so
window that's what the application keeps watching to say all
...indications down let's close this thing because we're done right windows
eight expects to use this uri format but that's not a url and
...ad saying I don't know-how to do how to
deal with this and the reason for that year...that
...happened was when you go treasury...
You create a new app and say want to create a new application right
you have these...options web application or native application what I
did wrong here is that I created a web application
...web application
expects a reply url that's http something.
Ok, now I say...I'm replying to nsf something
...that...can't possibly be right so what I
would do is I will fix that by create cannot application which
I already deed which is the.
The tree you be.
So, I see this is a web application three a this is a native
ep three-b so that's I already did those.
And, these one is correct has the right settings so what I would do is
...in order to change in our copy the new...id.
...are using here and outputting my
...and I have no idea where there is the eighties here.
And, say actually now...you are a lot...from the ad point of view I just
told you were completely different xml right and they'll try to run...again.
And, us...user name again.
...right because for a native...that's fine.
That's how you speaks this.
...and the worry this is...will be available laterthis is being recorded so you
guys have to worry about writing...every single thing they do here so,
this next scenario.
And, therefore.
Is an interesting one?
...where my where my where my.
K need to just
...is that because...going to break might example.
I think.
Right let's do it.
So,...this.
Connect...
Or good.
Then so I'll dedicated that's fine now I'm going I'm going
to ask for a excess token to these resource.
Right I want to call this things for need...access token for that thing that's a detail I'm using
the though here so I'm trying to do that
again there right.
And, let's see.
If I get their message here so
you can see what's going on result.
Blah-blah-blah.
So, that's terrible to read
right resource blah-blah-blah these able.
Your sharepoint site these
...so resource.
In a...terms is the thing I'm trying to excess I'm asking a cold
...can...that in this case sharepoint and the answer
...that sharepoint is disabled what sharepoint is trying to tell you
...these director using doesn't have office strata sixty-five I don't
know-how to give you access to thing that doesn't exist right either you don't have a license
...that doesn't have a license or you just don't have a subscription
role right.
...way you...is either.
Getting a subscription tying it to that directory or moving to how...my
...often...mistake because I'm using their own directory have directories that have office
...is five orders don't so I'm using the wrong one and that's how
you fix it right it's basically saying I don't know-how to give access to this.
Another interesting problem let-me open that one here and they can show you
...to go with that one.
Aidid something stupid because every simply have a windows it ep using the same
So, every time I have to go and stall.
Otherwise it will break my dems...anyway.
And, now we got a different similar but different
...so your client application is asking access to resource
blah-blah-blah so everything measuring the has these.
Id number if you are unique identifier for the
ad things right.
And, this particular case and saying this particular training thing you're trying to
...it's failed...calls.
Whoops the...has not specified is resource
...required resource...what does it...your application is trying to get
...token for something
and this application is not configured to use that thing.
...I should have configured application to use
that thing how do I go find out what's broken hear how I
fix it so let's look at this application first let's find out what's the
...id this is my claim the right so this is the scenario
So, if I go to my scenario five...the app.
And, these are the things.
Might...is allow to call my ep I give you the permission for my
...to talk treasury and
nothing else but I'm asking for permissions.
...erred.
Resource id so
...and...I...to get...excess looking for this one is it I don't know what is
...let's go find out what these this so I go treasury.
I go to search.
Applications that my company...of...these id here.
I'm trying to x these web application
probably web service that secure somewhere right in a trying-to get an
excess token for it is scope test
...any indeed that's not authorized
for these application so what I would do is I'll go to my clear this.
I will go to my scenario five.
...go to the configurations and...say I need to
A application crawled best amp.
That's...and ok.
Delegate a new
...stupid okay let's try again.
Very grew.
Click.
And,...dom quote-unquote key.
And, now we're seeing that's fine that's fine these app can do
that you can get an...so let's try to run it again ok.
Let's try to called this and if I didn't do anything wrong.
It's all good lawyers.
That's how my application now is allowed to use
...things saints I'll do this exactly the same if I wanted to give you the access to
...lying if I wanted to give it access to when dry for business
or something else right you have to preset that as a permission for your ep so
...try to
...mart and go do things you never thought it was allowed to do right.
Let's keep moving.
So, resource identifiers not provided that
starts I'm going up in terms of complexity in terms of
problems rights are...kind of if you have
...notice that yet so this is a.
This is a cool kind of ep.
This is a pure javascript zero
financier libraries just javascript on a browser nice good.
Via creation nice.
Ok, so, this is appear javascript so...he showed
...the secondary an application called the graphic api
...just javascript nothing else you can do that so this is how I'm doing the logo my redirecting
their browser to this logging windows dot net saying this is my directory
I want authenticate the user these my re-direct your...manually are not using any libraries
whatsoever and then this is how I get a token say one together token for this stuff here so,
this is just one-page this entire solutions one html page nothing else.
I will run this.
And, let me put that in private nodes so
...don't mess with my cookies.
And, I'll try to...scold so-you semi browser go to the local.
And, I got...here.
Look,...invalid
resorts resource identifier is not provided.
Again, what some resource it's the thing I want to access
right is the thing I'm trying to get access to any saying you're not telling me
what's that what's the resource you're trying to...this is very common when you do exactly what
...some authentication cold?
Instead of using the standard libraries or you just forget
...configuration which is exactly what I did here I'm asking for
permissions.
But, I didn't say.
Which resource I forgot the variable variables empty right I didn't say what I
want so actually this ensure the only one...give you the...
stoked right if you don't tell me I can help you right?
That's what I'm saying.
Can't recognize username or password let's see if I can find
...example here that's a cool one as well?
...scenarios seven and,
that so web...
That's the one.
Let's go over in this.
In private.
So, the reason why I'm not even see username or password
...boxes because I didn't close my audio private session so ad saying I already know
...logo mice year kooky so I'm not going to ask if I close all the browser
and start over...the user...so people get confused about...I didn't even
bypasses so that's a good thing because we try to not...posture all the time right we already know your
...respect that but in this case is saying well.
I don't know who you are right I can see you are
authenticated icu are the user blah-blah-blah but you are from
...external identity provider write your from these
id provider and these application can't understand who you are.
Right why is that the reason.
For this problem is that.
For this senators seven.
...accidentally.
So, this...my directory this is directory been using for all...was these
...my user...write the user one is here.
And, this scenario seven
...creating these directory I actually went to...directory and they
created a...seven there right...here.
So, it is saying I notice
...I know the user different places and you didn't tell me
that so ktwo to have them talking to each...either
uone that...in the right directory because these user is external to that
...directory or maybe...trying to do here is
...tenant...a...app...is a typical solution for
softwares a services right you create you have your directory you have a...
anyone customers from order organizations order directories to
...goal to your...from...directories without having to do the configuration
all over again one by one if that's what
you want their way you solve this problem is going to your application.
Any going to say these application is multi tenant.
When you do that you're saying sure now the
guys from whatever dot...company that use...they
use office rather sixty five or something like that those users can log on to my
...consent and...I'm fine using...and arguing to
...those guys...the resources from...directories,
for example, if I...the need a new cool email client for
exchange online right that's exactly what I would do I would create a new web interface
all create is...of...make it multi-band that are offer to anyone who
is a subscriber for all extract from office transitive five-two logan here and play with my
new...right that's how you do that the order option if that's not what
I one is just go in create...application the right place where the users are right
then is a single pennant only works in that directory...
So, that's there's seven.
Let me find scenario eight.
Lots of broken epsy here let's go scenario...
Estes one.
And, qa.
That's right.
So, this is similar this is also a
pure javascript I do this the reason why I like doing this like I would never do
this and production because I don't want to cussed custom-built that whole authentication authorization
called like their libraries that do this better however do but I like to have
...simple page like this because a great way of debugging a problem I eliminate everything else I
take away all the other libraries all the things that could possibly be part of the problem and
...can with the simple javascript call find out what's broken right and then
I can go back to the real application and go...an interesting way of debugging so...called...
Opened this year.
Same story pure javascript logan.
User you see that this dynamic close the browser windows so now I have to
...again right there...say I want to save anything.
And, this error message here.
Is saying the key?
Application with identifier blah-blah-blah was not
found in these directory ted one-one microsoft-dot-com so my directory skull that
might directly has...that one that's where my users are that's where my applications
are I'm saying application go-there and logo...user so the
...has its own klein id write it goes treasury these say these client these
...to log...the user and measure these say, yeah,
but, I don't know this...I don't have this up here.
...reason is that when I say I want to...
Right I have might tenant id
zone microsoft-dot-com I have my...and it turns
out these application does not exist here.
Is...so that's the same...
Where is...like the sm
...I know right in this directory so I cannot authenticated
and it's true because four that's an error which is the scenario eight?
If I look at it.
I really I won't find described id
...place I want find is...id here right I have order claimed
...here's what I can cia jump from.
I don't have the...
scenario there right I created somewhere else or maybe even forgot to created or maybe my
...ideas wrong I didn't...correctly right so it's not finding the right
ep log mean that's the problem how much of time...
So, there you go.
Just saying...not found...they're basically okay.
So, I try I try to put up a picture that
represents some areas that don't make sense at all that's what it came up with like it doesn't really make things I think
...that but anyway these are...ugly scenarios that
weird error messages that people say like what does it even meaning I don't even know what is
this so let's look at one of those scenarios this is a pretty cool one scenario
and nine.
So, what this error message means I have a...dot net?
Application here.
And, I'll try to do a...as well.
Out assigning.
Measuring the.
Right.
What is this?
what is the known snobs...a unique number that we use to avoid things like
...so what happens is before my browsers
...treasure ad to...I give the browser kooky with
a unique number nsa often go browser
...treasury when the browser comes back I go and ask if I had that
kooky back to met match the number if I cannot match the number or if the number doesn't
exist at all I cannot get the kooky back from the browser I will show this?
What this error means this I cannot find a kooky your browser
that I gave you just I mean...goal something is broken here and I
...that's a ripley attack and...stop you right what could be the...
anything that would lead a browser to not return a kooky back to the server
in this particular case if I look closely to fiddler?
Ioc that I'm accessing
...local host blah-blah-blah right I know the
local actually happen I know...happy with me send-me...that application
...is not a problem but when they started this...when I was here?
I was in the hate https.
Address.
Ideologue...and I was directed...
http address what the browser...doing this...cigna and not
give you the...gave me because you're different guy I don't know you write and will not
...local so if I do a trick here if I say well given if that's the case
what if I started with that order address like what if I started with these address?
Which is the null?
Https address they try to signing.
Under right because now I went back to the same place
I started from I got the kooky back from the browser I
know this is not a ripley attack we all happy right why I'm being
sent to the wrong place.
Reply address so this is the scenario nine.
If I look at my scenario ninety here what I did
wrong was saying that my reply...url.
Oops that's not...stop...here.
Right I started from https.
...redirected to http.
That's what breaks it common case
is you just went from development locally to the cloud
you are...your host name changes you forgot to change their your
...the wrong place or http to https your directed
...wrong guy...order common...well not so common...if you have
...in your host name that breaks...ever create...things with
underscored that's bad that's breaks, breaks...stuff don't do thatthe browser we refuse to
...kooky back when you do that so...anywhere where the browser
...say...give you the school...right will calls this error.
Right big thanks.
Let's go on.
Repost...token let's get that one that's
a very nice one q.
I think that's the scenario.
Me close my readers to...
...save this.
And, that's the scenario...
Put in here.
Today url.
...so that's.
That's a single page application single page applications are those
statefull javascript things where everything stays in one-page and all the logic is
...all the navigations done internally by the javascript so this angle r js
right and the happens that we have a they'll for include js which is great makes it easier.
I try to logo here user.
Logan.
Logan works great now what...is a course
call chords is when you go I'm on this website my javascript is going to call
was secure web service on order website right in this case...want to grab a
...token...disorder website.
Call web service without...gets embedded come back here
show it right it could be a could be calling one drive for business listing your my documents
...here so if I call this.
Let's see what happens.
Nothing happens why nothing happens.
Nothing happens because who worked here...I think I'm running their own let me see?
I'm...done something wrong.
Response type token is not supported by the application
gig so this is what we call...this...what we call.
Implicit flow my...now is spelling esri the
...a javascript client ria instead of going to the server...the service going to get
access token and come back I'm doing I'm doing this from the
client and doing a course call calling esri by
default we don't let you do that right for security reasons we by the
for setting is...the way I enable
...to do this is this scenario them so.
I'll go to mice and error ten...which is this one and they have a
manifest, manifest is where all your of deep
settings these app...saved and some of them are not for face
...the y so what...do is...download is manifest.
Open here.
Right that's my manifest and what I would do is saying I actually I'm actually
Implicit flow that's fine so save
...somewhere here that I can remember.
Like here.
And, now I will go back to my esri the and say
...manifest...
Get it for online.
Thing here which I think it's this one.
Saved right so ad now it's fine with this new setting a just
...let me close is all again.
Start over close these close this...
...getting really good at typing this is an image password.
Try to call my web service now let's see what happens.
Takes a little while.
Thanks...very little I think I'm doing something wrong because I think other group
so he called and got me a...hundred response.
Saying okay right so
...so,...have single page applications you have to do
these additional setting unfortunately that's not for faced in the
y so we have to open a manifests settings and do that over there okay?
The goal that's the setting.
That's a very...that's my favorite problem I...this problems I think it's a lot
of fun my this is the scenario eleven
...with dying okay five minutes we'll try to racially
...we have I think we have thirteen...sorter close.
So, these areI have a client in...server application
ok they're both in different sites...measure websites so
the...applications a javascript...that will do what I just
the before authenticate the user then via javascript I'll do course
call to my web...sand a ...token the web service
will polarized nsa shorten call my stuff here's my data all good when you do that
your every browser every modern browser when you try to do that you do a
pretty flight a brief like is an options request before...anything
...domain I'll call this order domain of ask are you expecting
need to call-you and same private user data these
...stalking like was you ever configure to do that or mia more likely to
be some cross script injecting attack here and this...reply say
...sure I I'm expecting calls...go ahead right that's the options
request...the options request this is an...
Are not going to st anything private to that
...before I'm confident I should do it so the options
require has no cookies
...authentication meaningful nothing about the user right before that
websites say sure go ahead what happens in this...
...that the web server is replying with
...q and saying go loading first and
that's makes absolutely no sense because that's exactly the point I...not
...you any load information before you tell me it's fine you should never reply with the three
or choose saying go loading right that's why it doesn't make sense so let's try to
reprobates let's see if I can...that here I'm not exactly sure.
If I configured is one right so let's go find out...
I have a measure website here.
And,...which one was it was the core
words collide esri and if I have been here sorry.
Scenario that scenario live out there go all
right so maybe that's going to define hopefully.
We'll call this thing I put this here.
That's an error one client I will.
And, actually
...enable...twelve so...can see that happeninguser.
Logan.
That's the wrong one is ...so this is the same
...I showed you before right reply addresses wrong because they're not supposed to
call this thing and that's because these was configure to be run on the
...that's fine...forgot about that so let's open those
...applications that scenario eleven client.
Which is this one...scenario...server which is...one?
Sorry I don't remember how I said these things up...always do that.
I actually think it once right.
Okay, I'm not sure and more anyways...not be able to
...configure correctly.
Let me go to the solution first...I messed up with
...configuration here somehow I'm pretty sure this was the right thing.
The reason why we get
is error is when you configure your web server so this is my server
right scenario eleven services leisure website when you configure leisure
...you have the super cool setting called ...
And, if you imagine you...a site
that has zero authentication called it you don't.
Anonymous any want-to make sure only your authorize users
are able to from your director able to use this site you have to options
...scold all of that to the right libraries make sure it's all set up the other option is
...can go to the measure website and do this?
Right...say just make sure
...lockdown for my users in my ...and what
this does it puts a...in front of your website that we make sure all the calls or
authenticated no matter what they are your website we never...never
...request if it's not authenticated and that makes a lot of things do
you do a briefly because this thing will block the brief light as well it wasn't meant to be using
that by the way fix it it's doing this?
...removing this.
Do...are proper
...with all...connect whatever library whatever platform you have
to make sure a you validated token so you cannot rely on the easy
oath for this kind of scenario otherwise you keep blocking
the options requests that's a solution...reprehensible up with something?
I have the samples online if
guys multiplicative so there you go you remove the easy alf and that's how you fix it.
The mysterious case of alta logo if there was a great case that's one of the best
developers vinyl so this happens with pretty much everyone
obviously it just happens he built and...
Here and he was a strictly for hours.
Because what happened was he was trying to logan.
I'm almost done like honestly I have just one more example then we're done.
He has this up here.
And, he does the logan.
open the right one that's twelve and he logs on.
At included here because there's guys one-seat.
Great.
And, log of.
I just did log on and I just lost my session what is going
on here and if you look at the fiddler you see that after the...I go back to the
site and then for some reason I go back treasury
d to the log out page.
What is means is that this site you somehow
...to send...browser to
goal golf it's something on this site?
Why am I going to with the browser one go-to vogel automatically write something
...saying go-there
...of...struggle this four hours until we sat together and we
search ok so let's think about this site you steadily their browser to
...so let's search for wherever in this
site where?
We call that...search for the entire solution that search for logo
Right so we have here today if you click in this...log out is an angle larger
...makes sense right that's
okay as a bunch of stuff here the angle...that we don't care.
A though we don't care about this stuff as well.
And,...look at.
So, this is...that a
...gives you the triggers wham loading succeeds.
And, what they deed accidentally there was some...
was let's buying...logo will...to this event?
So, what's happening is, yeah, you're lucky let's look...right.
And, super simple problem but people can spend hours trying to figure dissolved
it's it happens...part of life.
So, last one...was also another one that took several hours
and is one of those super simple problems...just open a...I won't run it so we
save time so we have a client javascript application and the web service?
Right and when you try to log...get and
...saying your audience sees rejected item
receptor all these all these is a setting to validate
...these excess token coming for the right place did we authenticate application
the right place right so what happens was everything was configure properly so I have my a
della js configure to...the web service together right token I have?
Everything set correctly here on the web service everything's fine to away when you look at my web comfy
...my audiences set correctly my client
these find everything's fine and it keeps getting all these rejected
...you search the code we found out that somewhere.
Opts...sorry.
And, you go back so that's the kind.
That's the...that singular js with a...also that some
valley I'm going to call the security point that's my claim id I'm calling is
...point right that's my web service.
And,...has some web configures here saying these my all the has this michael
...this might...right but for
some reason they messed up with this said...go to all we can say I'm going to use
...tokens from ...
Any stead of reading they all the in setting.
Which is these one...reading their
...id which is these one and these value turns out
is different than this value so we're not doing anything with this?
Two ways of solving this one is either saying well so my audience...the
...id...that value that we work our way of solving
...say well.
This is actually might all these so let's go fix the setting and you work common calls for
...as well is when you publisher application to a websites
in your web comfy gets...out because you're using the debug setting so that doesn't go
to the website and now I have to
...website a mainly set those values and you forget to do that with some of those setting so
he goes blank our doesn't match...everything works can open this these
access store can you can see the values everything looks fine but web service keeps rejecting
bed and because those values are not matching make things.
So, those are pretty much this scenarios I had to...today.
I hope you had fun
if you have more questions feel free to reach out to me so I had my twitter
on their my...is my first name dot my last name at...
happy to help you guys all with whatever questions you have thank you very much.